SUMMARY

Inquisitive data scientist with 1+ years' experience in an agile environment. Experience in product development and delivering data science insights using IBM Watson and GCP. Creative self-starter looking for data science opportunities to utilize software development and data science skills.

EXPERIENCE

IBM – Associate Data Scientist

July 2020 - Present

- Developed a customer service training solution with 6 possible outcomes and 10+ "What If?" scenarios using Watson Cloud Services
- Programmed an NLP scoring script to review Speech-to-Text input and output word error rate and inconsistencies in trainee's speech
- Conducted statistical testing on employees' metrics to provide insights on an employee's productivity
- Deployed new software functions to existing adaptive learning software product that reviews pilot training data and provides insights and recommendations through IoT data
- Constructed and updated report builders using Python and various libraries to improve validation of developer's code

Michigan Lottery – Graduate Capstone Project

September 2019 – December 2019

- Analyzed gameplay data to find patterns and insights about responsible gambling behaviors for online users
- Performed various statistical testing using Python and R to provide focal points for the Michigan Lottery team to understand their online users and gameplay patterns

Dunnhumby - Data Science Intern

May 2019 - August 2019

- Deployed classification algorithm and provided inventory recommendations to produce sales uplift of 1%-5%
- Classified products within a product category to recommend the most valuable products for restock based on retailer's financial and customer data

EDUCATION

Michigan State University – MS in Business Analytics

December 2019 | GPA: 3.9

University of Cincinnati – BBA in Accounting and Information Systems

May 2015 | GPA: 3.2

SKILLS/CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals | No Expiration

Technical: Python, R, SQL, JSON; Natural Language Processing, Data Visualization, Modeling

Software: Jupyter Notebook, GCP BigQuery, Visual Studio Code, Docker, GitHub, R Studio, Tableau